Sergio Villarroel

Full Stack Software Engineer

+1 707-440-9693 n www.sergiodev.com Software and Web Developer with 6+ years of experience. I've been involved in every step of web and software development implementing agile and scrum methodologies while generating extensive documentation of features, tests and results. My previous employments provided me with experiences and skills that allow me to effectively communicate remotely with team members and clients to achieve goals and customer satisfaction.

Relevant Experience

Senior Fullstack Engineer @ NaNLabs

May 2022 - December 2022 // Buenos Aires, Argentina

• Designed, tested and deployed an ETL Data Lake and workflow for joining and enriching multiple data sources implementing python, Docker, Spark, MongoDB, Serverless Framework and AWS Services (Glue, Lambda, EC2, DocumentDB).

SSR Software Engineer @ Newfold Digital

Aug 2021 - May 2022 // Buenos Aires, Argentina

- Refactored a classic wordpress marketplace from a monolith to a Micro-Service based platform improving response time, deployment times and all around stability.
- Designed, built and implemented an API Gateway, Kubernetes Cluster and micro-services which were deployed to AWS services.

Web Developer @ Freelance

April 2020 - Aug 2021 // Sacramento, CA

- Write modern, performant and robust code for a diverse array of clients and internal projects.
- Work with a variety of different languages, frameworks and content management systems such as JavaScript, React, Django, Node.JS. Python, Selenium, etc.
- Communicate and collaborate with multi/disciplinary teams of engineers, designers, clients on a daily basis

Java Developer & QA Developer @ Accenture

May 2017 - April 2020 // Buenos Aires, Argentina

- Managed a small team focused on developing a testing tool based in python and Selenium web Driver which applied a light layer of Machine Learning and Database feedback for testing new implementations automatically.
- Modified existing software of Oracle's billing and customer care application using Java, Hibernate and spring to correct bugs along with improving performance and upgrading interfaces.
- Worked closely with Project Manager in successfully migrating and backing up databases, restoring and updating the billing application for a major Argentinian energy company.

SAP Consultant @ IBM

May 2014 - December 2016 // Buenos Aires, Argentina

- · Consulted with clients regularly regarding projects, proposals, and technical issues that arise during the development process, while collaborating with other team members to determine the best design specifications and application of solutions.
- Designed and mapped internal workflows for legal, planning and confidential documents, and developed a file management system.
- Quickly learned Abap and provided support finding bugs and developing new solutions.



(github.com/sergiov13

Skills

Programming Languages

Python, Javascript (ES6), Typescript, GraphQL, MySQL, CSS, HTML, Bash, Shell Scripting, Postgress, MongoDB/DocumentDB.

Libraries & Frameworks

React, Gatsby, Node.JS, Flask, fastAPI, RabbitMQ, Django, Spring, Hibernate, Spark, Selenium, Serverless, TensorFlow.

Tools & Platforms

Git, Webpack, Netlify, AWS, Firebase, Docker, Trello, Jenkins, Windows and Linux.

Education

(Argentinian University of Business) 2016 - 2023

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science.

Courses

Automation with Python (by Google).

AWS Services for Data.

QA Testing of software solutions.

Advanced Java (Threads, 00, Servlets).

Hibernate, Java EE, JSP, JSF.

Maven Web Applications.

Projects

Music Rooms:

Web App built with Django, React and spotify API where you can create and join a room with a unique code and vote for next song or to skip songs.

Interests

Photography, Outdoor activities, Reading, Traveling and new technologies.

Languages

English (Native) Spanish (Native)